以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好吧，我很高兴回来，我
well ok I'm happy to be back and I'm
对项目提案非常满意
really happy about the project proposals
那是进来的
that are coming in
这就好，这是一个非常好的
this is like ok this is a really a good
课程的一部分，所以保持他们
part of the course and so keep them
如果和我很乐意给予
coming if and and I happy to give
无论我对这些反馈如何
whatever feedback I can on those
建议，并在那里开始
proposals and do make a start there
他们真的很好，如果有的话
they're really good and if if some are
在学期结束前完成
completed before the end of the semester
我们可以给生产提供机会
and we can give produce a chance offer
你有机会报告这些
you a chance to report on them that's
对那些人来说这太好了
that's good too so well done with those
建议所以我今天正在跳楼
proposals so while I'm today I'm jumping
第六部分
to part six
所以第六部分和第七部分是
so part six and part seven are
优化是最根本的
optimization which is the fundamental
进入深度学习的算法
algorithm that goes into deep learning
所以我们必须从优化开始
so we've got to start with optimization
每个人都必须获得该图片和
everybody has to get that picture and
然后部分7将是结构
then part seven will be the structure of
CNN的卷积神经网络和所有
CNN's convolutional neural nets and all
各种应用等等
that all kinds of applications and so
我们可以先从优化开始吗？
can we start with optimization so first
我能不能得到基本的事实
could I like get the basic facts about
泰勒系列的三个术语就是这样的
three terms of a Taylor series so that's
典型的是，我们很少会上升
typical it's seldom that we would go up
优化中的三阶导数
to third derivatives in optimization so
这是最有用的近似值
that's the most useful approximation to
一个功能每个人都在这里认识到它
a function everybody recognizes it here
我认为f只是一个功能
I'm thinking of f as just one function
和X只是一个变量，但现在我
and X as just one variable but but now I
真想去
really want to go to
更多变量，所以我需要做什么
more variables so what do I have to
如果f是更多的函数则改变
change if f is a function of more
变量所以现在我正在考虑X.
variables so now now I'm thinking of X
也没有让我看到我想要的
as well no let me see yeah I want n
这里的变量X是X1到xn所以是什么
variables here X is X 1 up to xn so what
它只是为了得到直截了当的话
it would just to get the words straight
所以我们可以开始对优化等什么
so we can begin on optimization so what
将是类似的步骤所以功能
will be the similar step so the function
f在X处记住X是n个变量没关系
f at X remember X is n variables okay
现在我有什么DeltaX呢
now what do I have Delta X so what
关于DeltaX现在有什么意义呢
what's the point about Delta X now it's
矢量DeltaX1到DeltaXn和什么
a vector Delta X 1 to Delta X n and what
关于F的导数它是一个向量
about the derivative of F it's a vector
相对于X的F的导数
to the derivative of F with respect to X
1是关于X2的F的导数
1 the derivative of F with respect X 2
等等等什么我有什么做的我
and so on so what do I have what do I
不得不改变我现在的那些
have to change about that I now those
伙计们是矢量，所以这是他们的点
guys are vectors so it's their dot
产品，所以它的DeltaX转置
product so it's Delta X transpose that
矢量时间这个DFDX所以是这样的
vector times this DF DX so what's the so
现在我正在取代所有人
this now I'm replacing this by all the
衍生物，它是渐变所以
derivatives and the it's the gradient so
的F在X上的梯度为
the gradient of F at X is the
衍生品让我们看到它至关重要
derivatives let's see it's essential to
直接在这里得到记号是的
get the notation straight here yeah so
它将是该的偏导数
it'll be the partial derivatives of the
函数f所以gradF是部分的
function f so grad F is the partial
F的衍生物相对于X1
derivatives of F with respect to X 1
向下偏导数的击到
down to partial derivative the strike to
考试还行，这是线性术语
exam okay good that's the linear term
现在什么是二次项1/2
and now what's the quadratic term 1/2
现在DeltaX不再是标量了
now Delta X isn't a scalar anymore it's
一个矢量，所以我将有DeltaX.
a vector so I'm going to have Delta X
转置和DeltaX以及进入的内容
transpose and a Delta X and what goes in
之间是二阶导数但是
between is the second derivatives but
我有一个n变量的函数和
I've got a function of n variables and
那么这是什么呢？现在我有了
so what does this mmm so now I have a
二阶导数矩阵
matrix of second derivatives right and
我会称之为H这是矩阵
I'll call it H this is the matrix of
二阶导数hJK是第二个
second derivatives h JK is the second
关于XJ和F的F的导数
derivative of F with respect to XJ and
XK又有什么名字这个家伙
XK and what's the name for this guy the
HessianHessian矩阵如何Hessians
Hessian Hessian matrix how the Hessians
钻进这张照片我不知道
got into this picture I don't know the
我认识的只有Hessians才是那些人
only Hessians I know are the ones who
为革命战争而战
fought in the Revolutionary War for
有人在我身边的那个人
somebody who which side were they on I
想想法国可能是错误的一面
think maybe the wrong side the French
在我们这边，是的，不管怎样，Hessian
were on our side and yeah anyway Hessian
矩阵和什么是事实
matrix and what what are the facts about
那个矩阵很好，第一个事实是
that matrix well the first fact is that
这是他们，关键的事实是它
it's them and the key fact is it's
对称的确定，再次，这是一个
symmetric ok and again that's an
近似所以所有人都参与其中
approximation so and everybody involved
认识到如果我们有乐趣，如果n是
recognizes that if we have a fun if n is
非常大，我们有一个功能
very large and we have a function of
许多变量然后我们有n个衍生物
many variables then we had n derivatives
计算这里和约1/2和
to compute here and about 1/2 and
使用一半的平方导数
squared derivatives using the the half
来自对称但关键
comes from the symmetry but the key
点是N平方变量
point is the N squared variables
衍生物来计算那里
derivatives to compute there so
如果n，计算梯度是可行的
computing the gradient is feasible if n
实际上是小的还是中等的
is small or moderately large actually
你用秋天
you by using autumn
分化背后的关键理念
differentiation the key idea of back
传播回来道具你可以得到你
propagation back prop you can get you
可以做到你可以加快计算速度
can do you can speed up the computation
衍生品相当惊人，但仍然
of derivatives quite amazingly but still
对于深度学习问题的规模
for the size of deep learning problems
因为这是这是如何达到这么好
as that's that's how to reach okay so
这是图片，然后我会想要
that's the picture and then I will want
解决使用这个解决方程式让
to solve use this to solve equations let
我有一个平行的图片给我们
me there's a parallel picture for us
矢量F所以现在这是一个向量
vector F so now this is a vector
这是X的F1到X的f
function this is F 1 of X up to f of X
X是X1到Xn所以我有n
and X is X 1 to X n so I have n
n个变量和函数的函数
functions of n variables and functions
n变量很好，这正是什么
of n variables well that's exactly what
我有一个想到的渐变
I have in the gradient that's think of
这两者是平行的并行存在
these two is parallel the parallel being
s对应于Fn的梯度
s is corresponds to the gradient of F n
n个变量的函数现在好了
functions of n variables ok ok so now
也许我在这里的目的是解决F.
maybe what I'm after here is to solve F
等于0所以我要考虑一下
equals 0 so I'm going to think about the
在F在X+δX所以它开始
the F at X plus Delta X so it starts
用f的X然后我们有
with f of X and then we have the
校正乘以第一个矩阵
correction times the matrix of first
衍生品以及它的名称是什么
derivatives and what's the name for that
一阶导数矩阵
matrix of first derivatives
好吧，如果我只给了n个函数而且我
well if I'm just given n functions and I
是的，我在这之后我的意思是什么
yeah what am i what am i after here I'm
寻找雅可比人，所以头发会去
looking for the Jacobian so hair will go
雅各比人J这是雅各比人
the Jacobian J this is the Jacobian
雅各比雅可比矩阵和
named after Jacobi Jacobian matrix and
JK条目的条目是什么？
what are its entries J the JK entry is
Jayce函数的导数
the derivative of the Jayce function
关于这个案子非常好
with respect to the case very okay and
我正在停止那里的第一顺序
I'm stopping a first-order there okay so
这些都是类似的事实
these are those sort of like facts of
你可以说1802的微积分事实
calculus facts of 1802 you could say
多变量微积分就是重点
multivariable calculus that's the point
注意我们正在做的就像
notice that we're we're doing just like
1802年上半年恰好不同
the first half of 1802 just different
微积分导数泰勒
differential calculus derivatives Taylor
我们不会做多个系列
series we're not doing multiple
积分不属于我们的世界
integrals that's not part of our world
这里好了，这就是背景现在我
here okay so that's the background now I
想看看优化还好吧
want to look at optimization okay okay
所以在这里我想要优化得很好
so over here I want to optimize well
让我试着最小化X的f
over here let me try to minimize f of X
我会在这里和矢量案例中
and I'll be in the vector case here and
在这里
over here
我想解决F等于零和
I want to solve F equals zero and of
当然这意味着F的意思是一个
course that means that means F of one
一直到FN等于零
equal to zero all the way along to F N
这里等于零我有n个方程式
equals zero here I have n equations let
我从那个开始，我会开始
me start with that one and I'll start
用牛顿的方法牛顿最好的
with Newton's method Newton the best to
在n个未知数中求解这n个方程
solve these n equations in n unknowns
好的，所以牛顿经常没有
okay so Newton which is often not
在1802年提出这是一种犯罪，因为
presented in 1802 that's a crime because
那就是那个大的应用
that's the that's the big application of
雅各比人的渐变好吧所以我
gradients in jacobians okay so I'm
试图解决n中的n个方程
trying to solve n equations in n
未知数，所以我希望F在X加Delta
unknowns and so I want F at X plus Delta
X为零，所以我想要X加上f
X to be zero right so I want f of X plus
DeltaX为零，因此X加上f
Delta X to be zero so so f of X plus
DeltaX是我把它归零
Delta X is I'm putting in a zero I'm
只是复制那个等式就是f在哪里
just copying that equation is f at where
我是X让我让K用这个案子
I am X let's let me use K for the case
迭代所以我在一个点XK我想
iteration so I'm at a point XK I want to
得到XK加一点，所以我已经0了
get to a point XK plus one and so I've 0
在那个时间点是X加J的f
is f of X plus J at that point times
DeltaX是XK加1减去XK
Delta X which is XK plus one minus XK
当然这是牛顿的方法
good that's Newton's method of course a
零是不完全正确的零
zero isn't quite true well zero will be
真正的对，如果我构建
true for the for the if I'm constructing
XK加一个我在这里构建XK
XK plus one here I'm constructing XK
加一个好，所以让我重写一下
plus one okay so let me just rewrite
那把刀，我们有牛顿的方法
that knife and we've got Newton's method
所以我们正在寻找这个
so we're looking for this
改变XK加一减XK我会把它
change XK plus one minus XK I'll put it
在这方面加上XK这就是这个
on this side s plus XK so that's this
现在我必须将其反转并将其打开
now I have to invert that and put it on
等式的另一面如此
the other side of the equation so
这将是一个减去这个家伙将是
that'll go with a minus this guy will be
颠倒和F在XK那是牛顿的
inverted and F at XK that's Newton's
方法自然让我再说一遍，
method natural let me just repeat that
你看到XK加1减去XK的位置
you see where the XK plus 1 minus XK is
城市权利，我把FXK转移到另一个
city right and I moved FX K to the other
一边用减号然后我
side with a minus sign and then I
乘以J逆，所以我得到了
multiply through by J inverse so I got
那
that
所以这是牛顿的系统方法
so that's Newton's method for a system
方程式，但在那里，我要去
of equations but over there I'm going to
写下牛顿的方法
write down Newton's method for
最小化功能这是基本的
minimizing a function this is such basic
我们必须从这里开始的东西让我
stuff that we have to begin here let me
甚至从极端开始
even begin with a with a extremely
牛顿的直截了当的例子
straightforward example of Newton's
这里的方法假设我的功能我
method here suppose my function I
假设我只有一个功能
suppose I've only got one function
实际上我想我只有一个
actually suppose I only have one
功能如此，所以我想我的
function so so I'm so suppose my
函数是x平方减去9而我想要的
function is x squared minus 9 and I want
解决X的f等于0我想找到
to solve f of X equals 0 I want to find
这个9的平方根好吧那又怎么样
this square root of 9 okay so what what
牛顿的方法是我们应该的
is Newton's method for it we just should
看到我的观点只是看看牛顿是怎么回事
see my point is just to see how Newton's
写入方法然后重写它
method is written and then rewrite it a
有点让我们看到有
little bit so that we see there
收敛好吧当然是这样的
convergence okay so so of course the
雅可比是2倍，所以牛顿的方法说
Jacobian is 2x so Newton's method says
XK加1我只是要复制
that XK plus 1 I'm just going to copy
那
that
减1超过2XK
minus 1 over 2 XK
这是X的衍生时间F.
right that's the derivative times F at X
K这是XK平方减去9好
K which is XK squared minus 9 okay
我们按照公式我们这个
we followed the formula we that this
确定XK加1，让我们让它
determines XK plus 1 and let's let's
简化它所以在这里我有XK-那
simplify it so here I have XK - that
看起来像XK的一半所以我想我
looks like a half of XK so I think I
有一半的XK然后这一次
have a half of XK and then this times
这是一个超过XK的9个半部分
this is 9 halves of one over X K is that
XK的右半部分来自这个东西
right half of XK from this stuff and
加上X的一半加上一半好吧
plus nine halves of one over X here ok
我能不能检查一下我是否知道
can I just like check that I know the
答案是三，我可以肯定我得到了
answer is three can I be sure that I get
正确答案3所以这就是如果
the right answer 3 so this was that if
如果XK当然是三个当然我
if XK was exactly three then of course I
期待XK加1保持3，所以做什么
expect XK plus 1 to stay at 3 so do what
这样做会发生在三分之一和
does that happen so half of three and
九个一半的服务是什么
nine halves of one serve what's that
三分之一和九分之一
half of three and nine halves of
三分之一没关系就是那三个
one-third okay that's that's three
六分之一和半分三分
halves and three halves at six halves
这三个还好，所以我们已经
and that's three okay okay so we've
检查方法是否一致
checked that the method is consistent
这意味着我们保留了代数
which just means we kept the algebra
笔直但后来真正重要的
straight but then the really important
关于牛顿方法的观点是这样的
point about Newton's method is this is
现在发现它收敛的速度有多快
to discover how fast it converges so now
让我DKXK加一减三所以
let me dou XK plus one minus three so
现在我正在看我的错误
now I'm looking at the error which is I
希望接近零
hope approaching zero
它接近零的速度有多快
is it approaching zero how quickly is it
接近零是这些
approaching zero these are the
因此优化的基本问题
fundamental questions of optimization so
我要从两个中减去三个
I'm going to subtract three from both
双方
sides
不知怎的，从这里好吧我想我会的
somehow okay from here I guess I'm gonna
减去三者可以我，所以我只是
subtract three can I just so I was just
检查它是否正确现在好了
checking that it was correct okay now so
XK加一减三我会
XK plus one minus three I'm gonna
从两侧减去三，我要去
subtract three from both sides I'm gonna
减去那里三，然后我希望
subtract three there and then I hope
就是那个盒子就是下来的东西
that that's that box is what goes down
这里右边两个减去了三个
here right subtracted three from both
所以我看着我希望它
sides so I'm looking at I'm hoping it
现在去希望事情变成零好吗
goes now hoping things go to zero okay
所以我有什么让我考虑因素
so what do I have there let me factor
超过XK1，所以我有什么
out the 1 over X K so what do I have
然后在XK上留下一个，所以有一个9
then left one over X K so there's a 9
XK上有一半，所以我
halves from there one over X K so I
真的有XK平方的1/2是因为
really have 1/2 of X K squared because
我除以nXK，这减去3我
I've divided by n X K and this minus 3 I
因为我是最好的减去3XK
better put minus 3 X K cause I'm
除以XKI声称这没关系
dividing by X K I claim that that's okay
现在我知道了
now I've got it
让我们看看让我拿出2来
and let's see let me take out the 2 to
忘了这两个人，让我成为一个6
forget these twos and make that a 6 so I
超过2XK倍9加XK
have 1 over 2 X K times 9 plus X K
平方减6对此有什么好处
squared minus 6 anything good about that
我们希望这一周我们希望那样
we hope so week we hope that that is
有吸引力的东西，所以这又是
something attractive so this is again
这是步骤K加1和1的错误
this is the error at step K plus 1 and
这个东西超过2倍XK的1倍
it's 1 over 2 X K times this thing in
括号9加XK平方减去6xk
brackets 9 plus X K squared minus 6x k
我们认识到，随着XK零下3
and we recognize that as X K minus 3
平方
squared
XK平方减去其中六个加上9个
XK squared minus six of them plus 9
这是XK减3平方好吧
that's XK minus 3 squared okay that was
目标当然是目标
the goal of course that's the goal that
显示为什么牛顿的方法太棒了
shows why Newton's method is fantastic
如果你能执行它，如果你可以开始
if you can execute it if you can start
接近通知那就是那个
near enough notice that so that's that's
所以我怎么形容这个伟大的
so how do I describe this this great
等式，它说错误是
equation it says that the error is
每一步都是平方的
squared at every step
如果我是的话，每一步都是平方的
squared at every step so if I'm
收敛到它会满足的极限
converging to a limit it will satisfy
这将是3或我猜减3
that it'll be 3 or I guess minus 3 is
那可能
that possible
是的减3是这里的另一个解决方案
yeah minus 3 is another solution here so
我们所以我们有两个解决方案
we're so we've got two solutions the
牛顿法可以收敛到凌晨3点我
Newton's method could converge to 3 am i
它可以收敛到负3所以我
right it could converge to minus 3 so I
我可以有一个类似的等式排序
could I'd have a similar equation sort
以-3为中心或者它是什么
of centered at minus 3 or what does it
总是做其中一个可能爆炸的事情
always do one of those it could blow up
它可以让所以这些都是有
it could so that so those are there are
那种有吸引力的地区
sort of regions of Attraction there are
所有接近3的起点
all the starting points that approach 3
而这个等式的重点是
and the whole point of that equation is
二次收敛的误差
with quadratic convergence the error
在它看来的每一步都被平方
being squared at every step it seems in
三，然后就是这一切
on three then there's a whole all these
可以去的起点
starting points that would would go to
减3然后他们开始
minus 3 and then their their starting
那些会爆炸的点数和
points that would blow up so and and
那可能是为了这个非常简单
those may be for this very simple
问题是，画面是不是太
problem that the picture is not too
很难理清那三个
difficult to sort out those three
区域，但如果我们有，这是
regions but if we had and this is
允许矢量
allowing for a vector
我们就是两个方程式或n个方程式
two equations or n equations then we're
在n个变量中，你真的得到了
in n variables and is really you get
美丽的图片你得到一些
beautiful pictures you get some some of
给出的图片类型有所增加
the type of pictures that gave gave rise
这些关于分形图的书籍
to these books on fractals the picture
关于分形的书-对于这些盆地
books on fractals - for these basins of
吸引力是否起作用
attraction does the does the starting
点引导您进入其中一个解决方案
point lead you to one of the solutions
或者它会引导你到达无限远
or does it lead you to infinity here it
只画画会很有趣
that would be interesting to just draw
这是好的，但必不可少的
it for this okay but the the essential
要点是它们是二次收敛
point is they're quadratic convergence
如果它足够接近你会看到它有
if it's close enough you see that it has
如果XK是X0则关闭
to be close if if X K is if X 0 is
非常接近3然后这是关于
pretty near 3 then this is about
六分之一，那将是一件好事
one-sixth of that and there'll be a good
在这种情况下吸引力区域没关系
region of Attraction in this case okay
这就是牛顿的方法
so that's that's Newton's method for
方程式，现在我想做牛顿的
equations and now I want to do Newton's
方法
method
我只想转换所有这些词
I just want to convert all those words
以牛顿的优化方法
over to Newton's method for optimization
所以记住这些板子
so remember the these boards were
求解F等于0
solving F equals 0
这个董事会正在尽量减少资本F和
this board is minimizing capital F and
他们之间有什么联系
what's the connection between them well
当然，当我们对应的时候
of course when we this corresponds to
如果我是的话，至少解决梯度问题
solving the gradient at a minimum if I'm
最小化我找到一个点所有
minimizing I'm finding a point where all
第一个导数是零，所以
the first derivatives are zero so so
这将是这些之间的匹配
that'll be the match between these that
在这张照片中这个正确的F是
that this right F in this picture is the
那幅画中的小F.
small F in that picture
好吧，我猜我在这里，这是
ok now I guess here I have and this is
我们的应用程序的核心
sort of the heart of our applications to
深度学习我们非常复杂
deep learning we have very complicated
损失函数以最小化函数
loss functions to minimize functions of
数千或数百
thousands or hundred
成千上万的变量还可以
thousands of variable okay so that means
我们想用牛顿的
that we would like to use Newton's
方法，但往往我们不能让我这样
method but often we can't let me so let
我所以我需要在这里放两个
me so I need to to put down here two
方法一不涉及那些
methods one that doesn't involve those
高二阶导数和一个a
high second derivatives and one a
牛顿这样做首先如此
Newton's that does so so so first so
首先，我会写下一个方法
first I'll write down a method that does
不涉及如此方法一和这个
not involve so so method one and this
将是最陡峭的下降，是什么
will be steepest descent and what is
那说XK加一个新的
that that says that XK plus one the new
X是旧的X减去我最陡的下降
X is the old X minus my steepest descent
意味着我进入最陡峭的状态
means that I move in the steepest
方向是哪个方向
direction which is the direction of the
FI的梯度移动了一段距离而我
gradient of F I move some distance and I
更好地有自由来决定那是什么
better have freedom to decide what that
距离应该是这一步
distance should be so this is a step
大小是或用深语
size yes or in the language of deep
学习它通常被称为学习
learning it's often called the learning
速率学习率还可以
rate learning rate okay so is that that
所以我们选择SK是很自然的
so and it's natural to choose SK we're
你一路走来看看这是什么
going along do you see where what this
右手边看起来像我在
right hand side looks like I'm at a
在n维中指出它们都是它
point in n dimensions they were all it
在这里我们有n个维度
were in n dimensions here we have
n个变量的函数有一个
functions of n variables there's a
向量有一个向下移动的方向
vector there's a direction to move down
图的最陡斜率
the steepest slope of the of the graph
这是移动的距离，我们
and here's a distance to move and we
将停止我们必须得到这个
will stop we'll have to get off this
如果我们坚持下去，通常会迈出一步
step normally if we if we stay on it a
小摇摆它会回来它会采取
little sway it'll swing back it'll take
我们走向无限
us off to infinity
等你想要选择SK
wait the the you would like to choose SK
这样你就可以减少资金F.
so that you minimize capital F you take
这一点上的这一点，这就是我
the point on this line so this is I'm
这是我们朝着一个方向发展的一条线
this is a line in our in a direction in
RN以及该线路上的所有点
RN and for all the points on that line
在那个方向F有一些价值和
in that direction F has some value and
你期望的是最初的
what you expect is that initially
因为你明智地选择了它的价值
because you chose it sensibly the value
F会下降但是会有所下降
of F will drop but then at a certain
指出它会转向你
point it'll it'll turn turn back on you
并增加，这将是
and increase so that would be the
自然停留点，那就是我
natural stopping point and that would I
会说这就是一个确切的线搜索等等
would call that an exact line search so
精确的线搜索将是确切的线
exact line search would be exact line
搜索是当然最好的感觉
search is the best sense of course that
需要时间来计算和你
would take time to to compute and you
可能在深度学习的时候
probably in deep learning that's time
你负担不起，所以你修复了学习
you can't afford so you fix the learning
你也可以选择点o1
rate s maybe you choose point o1 to be
非常安全，所以这是方法之一
pretty safe okay so that's method one
最陡的血统现在是一种方法二
steepest descent now a method two will
是牛顿的方法所以现在我们有了XK
be Newton's method so now we have XK
加一个我的两个XK减去一些时间
plus one my two XK minus something times
达美F
Delta F
现在我要做正确的事
and now I'm going to do the right thing
我要住在这里和右边
I'm gonna live right here and the right
事情是Hessian的第二个
thing is the Hessian the second
导致这就是这个
derivative that's what this is this was
便宜我们只是采取了方向和
cheap we just took the direction and and
现在我们真的开始了
went along it now we're getting really
使用第二个方向正确的方向
the right direction by using the second
导数使得H逆向可以和
derivative so that's H inverse okay and
我所做的就是将其设定为
what I've done is to is to set that to
零，所以你会看到那些
zero so that would be do you see thats
牛顿的方法
Newton's method
它与这个家伙完全平行
it's totally parallel to this guy
实际上，我很高兴有这些
actually I'm really happy to have these
两块板在板上相互平行
two on the board parallel to each other
因为你必须保持
because you have to kind of keep
直接你在解决方程式
straight are you solving equations or
你最小化功能，你是谁
are you minimizing functions and you're
在两者中使用不同的字母
using different letters in the two
问题，但现在你看他们如何匹配
problems but now you see how they match
比赛的雅各比亚再次如此
the Jacobian of so so again the matches
因为F为F的梯度是
think of F as the gradient of F that's
这就是你应该这么想的方式
that's the way you should think of it so
渐变的雅可比行列式是
the Jacobian for of the gradient is the
粗麻布雅可比的梯度
Hessian the Jacobian of the gradient is
Hessian，这是有道理的，因为
the Hessian and that makes sense because
我们采取的一阶导数
we take the first derivative of the
一阶导数是第二个
first derivative is the second
只有我们正在做矩阵的导数
derivative only we're doing matrix y so
这就是渐变的雅可比行列式
that's so the Jacobian of the gradient
我们正在做一个矢量矩阵句
we're doing a vector matrix sentence
而非标句
instead of a scalar sentence the
渐变的雅可比行列式是一个Hessian
Jacobian of the gradient is a Hessian
是的，没错，这就是我想要的
yep right okay so that's what I wanted
首先要获得那些基本的
to start with just to get those basic
事实下来，所以基本事实是
facts down and so the basic facts were
这是泰勒系列的三个术语
the were the three term Taylor series
然后是基本算法
and then the basic algorithms followed
自然而然地通过设置
naturally from it by setting the
如果那样，FF在新的点为零
FF at the new point to zero if that's
你在解决什么或者假设他
what you were solving or by assume he
现在有好一个好好好
had right good good good good okay now
现在我们要考虑解决什么问题
what now we have to think about solving
这些问题
these problems
他们研究的是他们收集的费率
studying do they converge what rate do
他们很好地收敛了
they converge well that's the rate of
收敛就像我采取的原因
convergence is like what I why I took
这分开了这个例子所以
this separated off this example so the
牛顿法的收敛速度
convergence rate for Newton's method
将是二次的，误差得到平方
will be quadratic the error gets squared
当然这意味着超级快
and of course that means super fast
如果你足够接近就会收敛
convergence if you start close enough
最陡峭的收敛率
the rate of convergence for a steepest
血统当然不是你不是
descent is of course not you're not
在这里摆弄错误，因为你
squaring errors here because you're
你只需要取一些数字
you're just taking some number instead
因此，正确矩阵的逆
of the inverse of the correct matrix so
你不能指望SuperSpeed这么一个
you you can't expect SuperSpeed so a
线性收敛速度
linear rate of convergence would be
对，你期望错误给你
right you expect that the error to you
我想知道错误是
would like to know that the error is
乘以一些人说的每一步
multiplied by said every step by some
恒定低于一个
constant below one that would be a
线性速率与be相比
linear rate where compared to be
乘以每个平方
multiplied by being squared at every
步骤，这将是我们的基本
step and so this will be our our basic
这是for的基本公式
this is the basic formula for for
大规模的真正大规模
large-scale for really large-scale
问题，当然有方法
problems and there are methods of course
人们会提出方法
people are going to come up with methods
他们有点像牛顿的便宜
that they're sort of a cheap Newton's
方法LevenbergMarquardt和它在
method Levenberg Marquardt and it's in
笔记在本节末
the notes at the end of this section at
我们将在六点结束
the end of the six point for that we'll
到达
get to
所以LevenbergMarquardt是一种
so Levenberg Marquardt is a sort of
廉价男人的牛顿牛顿的方法呢
cheap man's Newton's Newton's method it
不计算到Hessian但它可以
does not compute to Hessian but it can
但它说我可以欠我的
but it says okay I owe i from the
渐变我可以看到一个
gradient I can see a
你知道在黑森州有一个词
sort of one term in the Hesse you know
所以它抓住了那个词，但并不完全
so it grabs that term but it's not fully
完全二阶好，所以现在我们现在
fully second-order okay so now we're now
我们必须考虑问题和我
we have to think about problems and I
猜猜这里的信息是完整的
guess the whole the the message here is
我们的出发点必须是
and our starting point has to be
凸凸是关键词
convexity convexity is the key word for
这对于这些问题的解决方案
this for these for these problems for
我们想要最小化的功能
the function that we want to minimize if
这首先是凸函数
that's a convex function well first of
所有凸函数都可能
all the convex function is likely to
有一个最小和图片
have one minimum and the picture that's
在我们这个最陡的血统中
in our mind of steepest descent this
碗的图片碗是图表
picture of a bowl a bowl is the graph of
一个凸函数，所以我在转
a convex function so that so I'm turning
现在，我将离开那个董事会
to convexity now I'll leave that board
那是因为那非常重要
there because that's pretty crucial and
谈论凸凸的概念
speak about the idea of convexity convex
功能凸集让我们致电
function convex set so let's call the
X的函数f和典型的凸集
function f of X and typical convex set
将我称之为k好，所以我们只是
will be i'll call it k okay so we just
想要记住这个词能做什么
want to remember what does that word can
凸均值，你怎么知道你
convex mean and how do you know if you
具有凸函数或凸集
have a convex function or a convex set
好吧，让我先从凸集开始吧
okay let me start with convex set so
这是因为这是我的一般问题
it's a because here's my general problem
我希望你的凸最小化
my convex minimization which you hope to
你有很多应用程序
have an in many applications you do have
所以你最小化凸函数
so you minimize a convex function for
在凸集中指向如此
points in a convex set so that's like
理想的情况是理想的
the ideal situation that's the ideal
情况好吧得到的东西
situation okay get something
内部强大的凸起
inside something powerful convexity the
功能是凸的，所以让我画
function is convex and so let me draw
我们的凸函数与图形
our convex function with the graph
好的，所以我将绘制我们的凸函数说
ok so I'll draw our convex function say
碗，这是一个X和F的图形
Bowl so that's a graph of f of X and
那么这里是带X1和X的X.
then so here are the X's with X 1 and X
基数为2，X为f的图形
2 in the base and the graph of f of X 1
X2在这里好吧其实我在那边
X 2 up here okay actually I'm over there
我应该把这个功能叫做我
I should be calling this function f I
认为是的，是的，小F会
think is that right yeah little F would
是的，我是这个家伙
be there graining of this guy yeah I
这么好，所以现在我是
think so okay so so what now I'm
在某些X上超过X最小化
minimizing over X in over certain X's
并非所有的X都可以最小化
not all X's I might be minimizing for
例子K可能是ax所在的集合
example K might be the set where ax
在这种情况下，等于BK可能是a
equals B K might be in that case a
当I时，衬底或移位的子空间
substrate or a shifted subspace when I
说子空间然后1806提醒
said subspace but then 1806 is reminding
在我的脑海里，我只有一个
me in my mind that I only have a
当V为0但是我有你的子空间
subspace when V is 0 but I have a you
知道排序的子空间的单词
know the word for a subspace that sort
移动了罚款，所以我只是把
of moved over a fine so I'll just put
那个词倒了一堆词来学习
that word down a bunch of words to learn
对于这个主题，但没关系，所以这是它的
for this topic but okay so it's a it's
像飞机但不一定通过
like a plane but not necessarily through
如果B为0则原点不会出现
the origin if B is 0 it doesn't go
如果B不管怎么说还是我有
through if B is not ok anyway or I have
其他一些凸集让我放
some other convex set let me just put
这个
this
就像在基地说K，我做了
like said K in the base and did I make
它凸起我觉得我很幸运
it convex I think pretty good luckily I
所以现在有什么好凸设置做
did so now what well the convex sets the
约束因此这是约束
the constraint so this is the constraint
set约束是X必须是X所在
set constraint is that X must be X is in
集合K好吧，我把它画成凸面
the set K okay and I drew it as a convex
blob这里是一个例子，它是一个
blob here was an example where it's a
扁平不是斑点而是平坦的平面
flat not a blob but a flat flat plane
但是让我回到什么地步呢？
but what does let me come back to what
凸起意味着什么是凸起的
does convex mean what what's a convex
组
set
是的，我们必须这样做
yeah let's we have to do that should
之前已经这样做了
have done that before
在笔记中我有乐趣
in the in the notes I had the fun of
弄清楚如果我拿了两个，我是否选了两个
figuring out if I took two if I took a
三角形是一个凸集让我们正好
triangle is that a convex set let's just
确定这是一个凸集是什么
be sure so what's a convex set that is a
凸集因为如果我采取任何两个
convex set because if I take any two
集合中的点并绘制线条
points in the set and draw the line
它们之间保持在这个集合中
between them it stays in this set so
这是来自x1的任何边缘线的凸性
that's convexity any edge line from x1
到x2保持在设置好的所以
to x2 stays in in the set okay good so
这里是我的小锻炼自己有什么
here's my little exercise to myself what
如果我把两个三角形的联合全部
if I took the union of two triangles all
我想让你做的是这种
I want to get you to do is this sort of
事物可视化凸而不凸
thing visualize convex and not convex
可能性假设我有两个
possibilities suppose I have two one
三角形，即使它是钝的
triangle even if it was obtuse that's
还是向右凸
still convex right
没问题，但现在如果我把它们
no problem but now what if I put those
两个三角形一起取得联合
two triangles together take their union
好吧，如果我带他们坐在一个大
well if I take them sitting with a big
像我失去的差距我的意思是我
gap between like I've lost I mean I've
从来没有这样的机会，因为如果我
never had a chance that way because if I
拿了我的一个，如果它是联盟的
took one of my if it was the union of
这两个那么你知道我该怎么
these two well you know what I'm gonna
如果我在那一点上采取了这一点
say if I took that point in that point
当然，这一切都是愚蠢的
of course it goes outside stupid all
正确的东西有关，但什么，如果
right what about a but what if the
三角形如果那个三角形怎么样
triangles what if what if that triangle
下三角形重叠的那种
that lower triangle kind of overlaps the
上三角是一个凸集
upper triangle is that a convex set
你是对的，说不出原因
you're everybody's right saying no why
我如何看待那两者的结合
how do I see that the union of those two
三角形不是凸集你
triangles is not a convex set guys you
告诉我在哪里选择两点
tell me where to pick two points where
这条线很好，我从一条线上拿走了
the line goes out well I take one from
那个角落和那个角落里的一个角落
that corner and one from that corner and
他们之间的界限走了出去
the line between them went outside
所以你的联盟通常不会很好
so you Union is usually not convex well
如果我想到两套联合我的
if I think of the union of two sets my
心灵实际上自动去了
mind actually automatically goes to the
另一个相应的可能性
the other corresponding possibility
这是两者的交点
which is the intersection of the two
如果我采取交集，那么设置
sets so if I take the intersection of
两套现在有什么处理
the two sets now what's the deal with
那
that
什么时候我有两个三角形
what was the when I had two triangles
两个分开的三角形我们能做什么
two separated triangles what what can we
说说这两者的交集
say about the intersection of those two
三角形它是空的所以我们应该考虑
triangles it's empty so shall we regard
空集作为凸集是不是
the empty set as a convex set yes isn't
它是空的，所以它没有任何东西
it it's vacuous so it hasn't got any
问题吧
problems right
还好，但现在是交点
okay but now is the intersection is
如果我假设两个，那么总是凸出来的
always convex if I'm assuming the two
我们开始的集合现在就是这样
sets that we start with are now that's
交叉口的一个重要事实
an important fact that the intersection
凸集让我们只画一幅画
of convex sets let's just draw a picture
这显示了一个例子，那是什么
that shows an example so what's the
只是这个部分和它的交叉点
intersection just this part and it's
凸好你能不能给我一点
convex okay can you give me a little
证明了交叉点是凸的，以便
proof that the intersection is convex so
我在十字路口拿两分
I take two points in the intersection
让我开始测试是否
let me start the proof to test if
什么是凸的你怎么测试它
something's convex how do you test it
你在集合中取两个点
you take two points in the set in the
交叉，你想表明
intersection and you want to show that
他们之间的界限在
the line between them is in the
交叉路口好吗为什么这么好
intersection okay why is that so take
两个点在交叉点取x1
two points take x1 in the intersection
我们这里有两套，那是
of we've got two sets here and that's
交叉的象征，我们
the symbol for intersection and we've
在十字路口得到另一个点
got another point in the intersection
现在我们想看一下这条线
and now we want to look at the line
它们之间是从x1到x2的线
between them the line from x1 to x2
与那个人有什么关系呢
what's the deal with that one is that
完全在x1中的k1
fully in x1 in k1
为什么它完全在k1这我们拿了两个
why is it fully in k1 this we took two
在我看的十字路口的点
points in the intersection I'm looking
在他们和我之间的界限
at the line between them and I'm asking
它是在第一组k1和答案
is it in the first set k1 and the answer
是是的
is yes
因为那些点在k1和k1
because those points were in k1 and k1
是凸的，是它们之间的那条线
is convex and is that line between them
在k2是的，同样的原因X两个
in k2 yes same reason the X the two
端点在k2所以之间的界限
endpoints were in k2 so the line between
它们在k管所以交叉
them is in k tube so the intersection of
凸集总是凸出来的
convex sets is always convex the
凸起的交叉点
intersection of convex
这很好，所以你会在笔记中看到
it's good so you'll see in the notes
两个三角形的这些可能性
these possibilities with two triangles
有有时你可以你可以采取
there's sometimes you can you can take
联盟，但不是经常
the Union but not very often
好吧，现在我接下来的是什么
okay now what's what's the next thing I
必须做我们得到的凸函数
have to do convex functions we got
凸集什么是凸函数
convex sets what are convex functions
那么我们是对的，因为这是
then we're good right because this is
我们这是我们问题的原型
our this is our prototype of a problem
我现在想知道它意味着什么
and I now want to know what it means to
为了那个F我是一个自信的人
be for that F to be a confident I'm
抱歉，我现在知道它对于这意味着什么
sorry I now know what it means for the
说K是凸集但现在我有
said K to be convex set but now I have
往往更多地看待对方
to look at the other often more
这个问题的重要部分是什么
important part of the problem what's the
功能我正在最小化，我在寻找
function I'm minimizing and I'm looking
对于这种类型的函数
for functions with this kind of a
图片没关系
picture okay
最酷的方式是连接
the coolest way is to connect the
凸函数的定义
definition of a convex function to the
这是凸集的定义
definition of a convex set this is
这是最好的方式
really the nicest way it's a little
快速它只是由你切换，但告诉
quick it just switches by you but tell
我，你看到一个凸集
me do you see a convex set in that
图片中你看到了一个凸集
picture you see a convex set in that
图片这是一个图的图片
picture that's the picture of a graph of
凸函数它是a的图片
a convex function it's a picture of a
碗是那个表面上的点
bowl is are the points on that surface
是一个凸集肯定不是
is that a convex set no certainly not
没有，但在哪里可以找到凸集
no but where is a convex set to be found
在那张照片中是的是积分
here in that picture yes yes the points
在碗里面和上面的里面
on and above the bowl the in inside the
碗，我们可以说这些点是如此凸起
bowl we could say these points so convex
功能我是一个功能时，凸
function me yes a functions convex when
图表上方和上方的点
the points on and above the graph
我们的凸集是的，这就是你
our our convex set yeah this is you
我的数学家可以说好吗
could say okay math my mathematicians
只是懒得有一个
are just being lazy having got one
定义直凸说
definition straight for a convex said
现在他们只是用它来给出一个
now they're just using that to give an
容易定义凸函数
easy definition of a convex function
实际上它是功能非常有用
actually it's quite useful for functions
这可能等于无穷大
that could maybe equal infinity sort of
一般的广义函数，但它
general generalized functions but it's
不要告诉我们，如果最快的方法
not the quickest way to tell if the
功能是凸的，这不是我们平常的
function is convex it's not our usual
测试凸函数所以现在我想要
test for convex function so now I want
现在我给这样的测试好了
to give such a test okay so now I
凸函数的定义平滑
definition of convex function smooth
是的，这个事实不要急于求成
yeah yeah the the this fact don't rush
在俄罗斯关闭远离它从从
in Russia off away from it from the from
凸函数的定义为
the definition of a convex function as
在其图形上方具有凸集
having a convex set above its graph
这里有一个非常官方的法国名字
there's a really official French name
对于上面说的那个图是
for that said above the graph is the
题词还好，因为我为什么回来
epigraph okay because why do I come back
那一分钟，因为我愿意
to that for a minute because I would
想想F1的两个功能
like to think about two functions F 1
我可以用两个函数中的F2
and F 2 out of two functions I can
始终创建最小值或最大值
always create the minimum or the maximum
所以我想我有两个凸函数
so I suppose I have two convex functions
凸函数F1和F2
convex functions F 1 and F 2
好吧那我可以选择最小的我
okay then I could choose the minimum I
可以选择我的新功能应我
could choose my new function shall i
称它为m，最小M为X.
call it little m for minimum M of X is
最小的f1和f2，我可以
the minimum of f1 and f2 and I could
选择这将是一个最大的功能
choose a maximum function which would be
X的f1和X的f2的最大值
the maximum of f1 of X and f2 of X at
同一点X，如果我只是一个
the same point X if I it's just a
自然的东西好吧我有两个功能
natural thing okay I have two functions
我有一个碗，我还有另一个
I've got a bowl and I've got another
碗，并假设它们都是凸起的
bowl and suppose they're both convex so
我只是在这里伸展你的东西
I'm just stretching you the thing here
如果我有，我有两张图
if I've got I've got the graphs of two
凸函数，我想
convex functions and I would like to
考虑这两者中的最小值
consider the minimum of those two
功能以及最大功能
functions and also the maximum of those
我相信你知道生活的两个功能
two functions I believe you know life is
好的其中一个将是凸的和
good one of these will be convex and the
其他不会，你能辨别哪个
other won't and can you identify which
一个是凸的，哪一个不是
one is convex and which one is not
凸起最小的是a
convex what about the minimum is that a
凸函数所以只看一下
convex function so just look at the
图表最小化的样子
graph what does the minimum look like
最小的是这个家伙，直到他们见面
the minimum is this guy until they meet
某种程度上在某种程度上然后这个
somehow on some surface and then this
家伙是我们喜欢的凸起
guy is that convex we have like one
分钟回答这个问题
minute to answer that question
绝对不会有这个糟糕的纠结
absolutely no it's got this bad kink in
关于它的最大的两个是什么
it what about the maximum of the two
函数，所以最大的是那个
functions so the maximum is the one that
它首先是所有要点
it's above all the all the points that
是或在上面或上面的东西
are or things that are above or on on
那里有那里的
the there there's the there's the
最小功能是最小的
maximum function that was the minimum
功能它最大扭结
function it had a kink the maximum
功能就是这样，它是凸的
function is like that and it is convex
所以最大的是
so maximum yes
至少知道，如果我们，我们可以最大化
minimum know and we could max if we
最多可以有1500个功能
could have a maximum of 1500 functions
如果1500个函数都是凸的
if the 1500 functions are all convex the
最大的将是因为它是部分
maximum will be because it's the part
每个人的图表以上的方式
way above everybody everybody's graph
这将是图表
and that would be the graph of the
最好还好
maximum okay good
现在终于让我只说怎么办
and now finally let me just say how do
你知道函数是否是凸的
you know whether a function is convex
如何测试切斯特
how to test out of Chester
好的，所以让我只是一个功能
okay so let me take just a function of
一个变量是什么测试你
one variable what's what's the test you
学习微积分新生微积分
learn in calculus freshman calculus
实际上只是表明这是一个凸起的
actually just show that this is a convex
功能什么是什么是测试为
function what's what's the test for that
二阶导数应为正数或
second derivative should be positive or
可能为零所以二阶导数
possibly zero so second derivative
更大等于零无处不在
greater equals zero everywhere
这是凸出的最后问题
that's this convex okay final question
假设F是一个向量，所以这是一个
suppose F is a vector so this is a
向量，所以我有n个n函数
vector and so I have n functions of n
变量不，我没有
variable no I don't have one
抱歉，我有一个功能，但我在n
sorry I've got one function but I'm in n
变量，以便使这只是一个
variables so so this was just one that
什么是凸性的测试是的呢
what's the test for convexity yes so it
将通过例如x1传递
would be passed for example by x1
平方加上x2平方就可以了
squared plus x2 squared would it be
通过所以这里将是问题
passed by so here would be the question
是否会通过X转置一些
would it be passed by X transpose some
对称矩阵F将是一个
symmetric matrix F that would be a
这是纯二次的二次方
quadratic the pure quadratic would it be
凸
convex
这将是测试它有我
what would be the test it's got I'm
寻找一个n维等价物
looking for an n-dimensional equivalent
正二阶导数的
of positive second derivative the
n维等价的正面
n-dimensional equivalent of positive
二阶导数是凸性和我们
second derivative is convexity and we
想要它我们必须认识到它是什么
want it we have to recognize what's the
测试所以我可以应用它
test so I could apply it to this
功能或我可以将它应用于任何
function or I could apply it to any
n个变量的功能好吧什么的
function of n variables okay what's the
在这里测试我有一个矩阵代替
test here here I have a matrix instead
一个数字，那么什么是好的
of a number so what's what's a good
要求是x出是的
requirement going to be x out yeah
正定或半定或
positive definite or semi definite or
就像这里一样半确定是的
semi definite just as here yeah so the
测试是正半确定是的
test is positive semi definite yes yes
这里黑森州实际上是
and here the Hessian is actually that is
因为二阶导数会
because the second derivatives will
第二个产生输出1/2
produce output 1/2 in there the second
衍生物将产生相等的
derivatives will produce s equal the
HessianH所以这里的S如此积极
Hessian H so this here the S so positive
半定的Hessian一般第二
semi definite Hessian in general second
二次方的导数矩阵
derivative matrix for for a quadratic
好吧那么那些凸出的问题
okay so so those it's convex problems
那我们要走得更远的地方
that where we're going to get farther
我们跑进去没有马鞍点
with we run into no saddle points we run
一旦我们找到了，就没有当地最低限度
into no local minimum once we found the
至少这是全球最低限度
minimum it's the global minimum these
好的问题好吧再好开心
are the good problems okay again happy
to see you today and I look forward to
看你今天和我期待着
星期三
Wednesday